Welcome back, Preppies.
Welcome to the next lesson of the IELTS Speaking Intermediate Course from PREP.
Today we're going to learn how to describe a city that you
have visited in a way that will leave a lasting impression on examiners.
Mastering how to handle this question will also help you apply it
to other questions that involve describing a location such as, describe
somewhere you have lived or where you would like to live, describe
a place you have been to, where there were lots of people,
describe a place away from your home and you would like to
visit in the future, describe a place where you would go to relax.
Alright, no more delay, let's begin.
Your task is to create an outline to handle the following question.
Describe a city that you have visited, where it is, when and
with whom you went there with, what activities you did there and how you feel about that place.
To achieve a band score of 6 plus in IELTS Speaking,
it is important to be highly graded on the fluency and coherence criteria,
which accounts for 25% of the total score.
In order to achieve this, your answer should be fluent, reasonably long,
ideally lasting for 1 minute and 40 seconds or more to avoid
losing points, and closely aligned with the task requirements.
However, when it comes to describing a place, many candidates tend to
focus on describing the location, but end up with relatively short speeches
because it is challenging to remember a lot of information about a place to speak for a full 2 minutes.
So today, I'll introduce to you a technique that will help you
meet both criteria, effectively describing a location and extending your answer.
It is Storytelling Technique, the art of telling a story.
This technique is essentially an advanced version of the technique, Sharing
Experience, used in IELTS Speaking Part 1.
However, for Part 2, you need to speak longer, so you need
to transform a past experience into a complete story.
What are the advantages of this technique?
Storytelling allows you to expand the story, which can be applied to
various topics, thereby helping you to avoid running out of ideas.
It also helps to organize ideas more flexibly by using linking words to add information.
So what makes a good story?
A good story should include elements such as setting, the place, characters, and a logical plot.
Based on these four elements, I'll provide you with a general outline
that can be applied to different types of topic questions.
In the introduction, we'll introduce the subject of the speech.
So we need to answer the question, what is the subject you will talk about?
For the background information, we need to provide the context, including the
characters, involved, the location, and the time of the story, and the cause that led to the main event.
So we'll answer the following three questions.
Which characters will be included, related to the thing or event?
When and where does it take place?
What was the cause of the main event?
Moving on to the main event, we need to narrate the order
of the events that occurred in timely order.
So we will answer the question, what happened in the main events?
Finally, we'll express our emotions or feelings about the subject or experience.
And we'll conclude by answering the following two questions.
How do you feel about the subject or the experience?
Do you have any intentions based on the story experience that you were just told?
These questions are suggested prompts to help you understand the content of each part in the story.
However, when it comes to a specific topic question, you'll need to
adjust accordingly to fit the questions in the cue card.
It is important to ensure that you answer all the questions in the cue card to avoid losing points.
To help you have a clearer understanding, let's apply this template to
brainstorm ideas for the question to describe a city that you have visited.
Describe a city that you have visited.
Where it is.
When and with whom you went there.
What activities you did there.
How did you feel about that place?
For the introduction, I'll introduce the subject based on the cue cards.
So I'll answer the questions.
What is the place and where it is?
Additionally, to provide more detailed information, I'll answer the question, what is this place famous for?
Moving on to the background information.
Based on the sample question, I'll talk about the time I started
the trip, who I traveled with, and why I went on this trip.
So I'll need to answer two questions.
When and with whom did you go there?
And why did you go on this trip?
For the main events, I'll provide a detailed description of the places
I visited and the activities I engaged in during the trip.
Additionally, since the purpose of this speech is to describe the city,
I'll also provide some information about the visited destinations, so I'll
answer the following three questions.
Where did you go and how were those places?
What activities did you do there?
Lastly, for the feelings, I'll certainly express my emotions and impressions about the city I'm describing.
I will also mention my future plans or intentions regarding the city.
Therefore, I'll focus on the following question.
How did you feel about this place?
Do you have any intention relating to the city?
So, I've just used the original template and created a specific template
to brainstorm ideas to describe the city.
Now, based on these guided questions, I'll take a specific example as follows.
Romantic beauty and rich cultural heritage.
Background information.
When and with whom did you go there?
Last summer with my family.
Why did you go on this trip?
It was a gift from my dad.
Main events.
Where did you go and how were those places?
What activities did you do there?
We went to see the Eiffel Tower, one of the most recognizable landmarks of the city.
Enjoyed the views of the city from the Eiffel Tower.
Explored the Louvre Museum.
Walked along the river Seine.
Explored Montmartre.
Feelings.
How did you feel about this place?
It lived up to my expectation and the people were friendly and it was beautiful.
There was a sense of community and a feeling of discovery.
Do you have any intention relating to the city coming back one day?
Let's review the template for a story.
To master these techniques, don't forget to practice regularly, preppies.
Now, let's call it a day.
See you guys in the next video.
Bye bye.